# Phillip Kane Rhee

I am a focused and energy-driven creative with a sharp analytical skill set honed through a Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and work experiences in marketing analytics and data science. As a self-motivated problem solver, I strive to present a holistic set of efficient and optimal solutions both to the front end of business, as well as to the technical end that makes our business infrastructure possible.

6930 Balboa Blvd Unit #16856 Van Nuys CA, 91402 818.625.7075 kanerhee@gmail.com

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Data Analyst Los Angeles, CA— J2 Global, Inc.

June 2018 – Present

- -Business Performance, Reporting and Visualization Developing measurement strategy with primary (funnel-related) and secondary (retention and fiscal) KPIs (i.e. Signups, Net Adds, Cancels, Average Revenue Per User, Lifetime Revenue, Churn Rates) building out automated dashboards, reports, and models to help teams make faster better decisions
- -Deep-Dive Analysis Scripting algorithms with big data to analyze user behavioral data to identify patterns, uncover opportunities, and create common understanding of how people are interacting with products and content.
- -Forecasting and Opportunity Sizing Implementing machine learning algorithms (Regression forecasting, K-means clustering, Decision-Tree Classification, ANN) to optimize lead capture and retention strategy for software as a service products.
- -Stakeholder management Partner cross-functionally with product/marketing/Engineering departments to identify opportunities using data.

## **Analyst, Digital** Santa Monica, CA—*RPA*.

October 2018 – Present

- -Planning Measurement Frameworks to research which collected data drive the most value, actualizing business KPIs from these data points, and executing front end and back end strategies to optimize consistency then growth of these KPIs.
- -Built out automated and enterprise reporting on digital platforms (client facing and non-client facing) for Honda Automobiles, Honda Tech Tutor, Honda SalesTraining, Honda & Acura Dealership Advertising Associations, ARCO Southwest, and ARCO Mexico.
- -Building Tag Specification Decks to implement website tags and collect data from user activity on clients' websites conducting QA tests of tags in all developer environments (DEV, STAGINE, etc).
- -Pulling and cleaning 1st and 3rd party data and developing key insights to enhance or refine content and media optimization strategy.

## Digital Marketing Intern (Web/Ad team) Hollywood, CA—J2 Global, Inc.

June 2018 – August 2018

- -Assistance with SEO, SQR, and SEM across Google Ads, Bing Ads, and Yahoo Gemini. Analyzing results with an emphasis on consistently improving CPA and CTRs.
- -Pulled and Analyzed KPIs for our brands and campaigns to help shape historical context for performance using DOMO, Kenshoo, and other marketing assistance platforms.
- -Ad Copy for Fax.com, eVoice, eFax, SugarSync, and LiveDrive creation of 152 unique ads to be applied across all ad groups and campaigns in Google Ads
- -Created and maintained tri-weekly performance reports for revenue forecast, product feasibility plans, and go-to-marketing strategy for B2B and B2C clients.

#### **LANGUAGES**

- -HTML/CSS
- -Python
- -C++
- -SAS
- -SQL
- -MATLAB
- -LaTex

#### **PROF SKILLS**

- -MS Excel (+ Office Suite)
- -Tableau
- -Adobe Analytics
- -Adobe DTM
- -Adobe Launch
- -Google Ads / Analytics
- -Yahoo Gemini

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

- -Kiva Nonprofit Club
- -Sigma Phi Epsilon (RLC &
- Communications)
- -St. Jude Children's Hospital's The Happy Cart Project

## **EDUCATION**

## University of California, at Santa Barbara

**Mathematical Sciences BS** 

- -3.01 GPA Overall
- $\hbox{-}3.00~\hbox{Major GPA}$